Tomas Makaj

Mahopac, New York | 914-483-6097 | tmakajcoding@gmail.com LinkedIn | Github | Medium | Portfolio Website

Software Engineer

Experienced in Ruby on Rails, JavaScript and ReactJs based programming and a background in Construction Project Management. Possess strong skills in problem solving, time management and is extremely detail-oriented. Takes pleasure in addressing day-to-day problems as challenges to better my own skills.

Technologies and Languages

JavaScript, React, Ruby, Rails, Redux, SQL, PostgreSQL, Heroku, Postman, Sinatra, Git, CSS

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Not Shake Shack - Github

Food ordering app for restaurant brick and mortar locations.

- Utilized JWT Web Tokens and localStorage to store encrypted user information client-side
- Engineered functional backend database allowing it to be self-sustaining using Ruby on Rails.
- Created the frontend using ReactJs allowing the user to navigate the website and update data as needed
- Created a transparent checkout cart allowing users to remove items from cart.

Lucid Real Estate - Github

Housing app that allows a user to add homes to their portfolio

- Built a backend database using Ruby on Rails
- Enabled ReactJs front end to fetch and render all the information from the database
- Crafted a sign in modal to persist on the frontend with scroll
- Distributed different data from the database by using multiple useEffects

The Hype Hut - Github

E-Commerce app for consignment shops and small businesses

- Integrated a stripe checkout using the Stripe API
- Created the backend and database using Ruby on Rails, Postman, and PostgreSql
- Incorporated Bootstrap Carousel on the landing page
- Utilized JWT Web Tokens and localStorage to store encrypted user email and password

EXPERIENCE

Taconic RemodelNew York, New YorkProject Manager06/2020 - 01/2022

- Managed various renovation projects.
- Coordinated all parts of the renovation process and worked with various teams to ensure completion.
- Developed and managed project timelines, resources and budget.

Majestic Home Improvement

Assistant Project Manager

New York, New York 07/2019 - 02/2020

- Assisted the project management of renovation projects.
- Consulted with clients on progress and worked with management to resolve any issues.
- Assigned and prioritized tasks for the construction team on a daily basis.

EDUCATION

Flatiron School

Fordham University

New York, New York 08/2022 - 11/2022

Full Stack Web Development

New York, New York 08/2014- 05/2018

Organizational Leadership/ Bachelor of Arts